JINKI JUNG

Email: your.jinki.jung@gmail.com / (secondary) jinki@dmc.international

Office: Bülowsvej 40, stuen Frederiksberg, Denmark Personal webpage: https://jinkijung.github.io/

Citations: http://scholar.google.co.kr/citations?user=inzigzUAAAAJ&hl=en&authuser=1

HIGHLIGHT

Jinki Jung is a senior software developer of Digital Maritime Consultancy, contributing mostly technical aspects of Maritime Connectivity Platform (MCP), one of the biggest open-source platform in maritime industry, as a system architect, a full-stack developer and a cyber-security expert. Previously he was a researcher with Augmented Reality/Virtual Reality/Human-Computer interaction background leading international and happy collaborations for safety-critical issues in pragmatic uses of those technologies. His personal interest for the time of writing is modeling a task for collaborations of human and intelligent machine in his very small but interesting project, Tasc.

EDUCATION

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Ph.D., Computer Science

Research Topic: Mobile Augmented Reality 2009-2015

Dissertation: "Real-time Sensor Fusion based Mobile Augmented Reality Framework"

Advisor: Hyun S. Yang

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

M.S., Computer Science 2009

Research Topic: Natural User Interface for Augmented Reality 2007-2009

Thesis: "A Real-time Robust Body Part Tracking System for Intelligent Environment"

Advisor: Hyun S. Yang

Soongsil University

B.S., Media Engineering 2007 **2003-2007**

CAREER

Digital Maritime Consultancy, Denmark

Senior Software Developer, Secretariat of MCP Research Topic: Massive Ship Traffic Simulation

esearch Topic: Massive Ship Traffic Simulation 2019-

Korea Research Institute of Ships and Ocean Engineering (KRISO), Republic of Korea

Postdoctoral researcher, Maritime Safety Research Division Research Topic: Virtual Reality for Maritime Safety Training

Context Awareness for Maritime Safety 2016-2019

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST), Republic of Korea

Postdoctoral researcher, Information and Electronics Research Institute

Research Topic: Egocentric Hand Interaction using Depth Camera

Virtual Reality for Maritime Safety Training 2015-2016

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Language: C, C++, Java, Objective C, Python, Typescript, Javascript

 $\textbf{Mobile Programming:} \ iOS, And roid$

Front-end: React, Angular,

Back-end: Spring boot, Node.js, NestJS **Graphics Engine**: Unity3D, UE4, OpenGL

PROJECTS

Maritime Connectivity Platform (MCP) - https://maritimeconnectivity.net

Senior SW developer / General, IDSec, MSR and MMS WG member

Contributing implementation of MCP core components including MIR (PKI, digital certificate, OIDC, HSM and MIR specification/installation/documentation), MSR (Distributed ledger, Blockchain, Spring boot application backend and React-based web front-end) and MMS (high-level description)

March 2018 - Now

JINKI JUNG PAGE 2

Sept. 2020 - Dec. 2020

March 2018 - Now

Maritime Object AI Data - https://aihub.or.kr/aidata/34155

Annotation tool & DL developer (https://github.com/Digital-Maritime-Consultancy/VoTT/tree/0.7)

Developing an annotation tool for Korean national project establishing a maritime object image database and a panoptic segmentation model for validating the database

Task script (Tasc) - https://tasc.readthedocs.io/en/latest/

Lead researcher

Establishing Task, which is a task script describing a sequence of tasks through building-block approach and developing a working demo of the idea

PUBLICATIONS

International Journals

Discipline vs guidance: comparison of visual engagement approaches in immersive virtual environments

Hyeopwoo Lee, Jinki Jung, Heung Kyu Lee, Hyun Seung Yang

Multimedia tools and applications 2021

Effects of interface on procedural skill transfer in virtual training: Lifeboat launching operation study

Jinki Jung, Young Joong Ahn

Computer Animation and Virtual Worlds 2018

Efficient mobile AR technology using scalable recognition and tracking based on server-client model

Jinki Jung, Jaewon Ha, Sang-Wook Lee, Francisco A Rojas, Hyun S Yang

Computers & Graphics 2012

Real-time recognition and tracking for augmented reality books

Kyusung Cho, Jinki Jung, Sang-Wook Lee, Sang Ok Lim, Hyun Seung Yang

Computer Animation and Virtual Worlds 2011

Domestic Journal

A Virtual Sailor Training Platform for Fire Drills on Ship

Jinki Jung, Jin Hyung Park

The Journal of Navigation and Port Research 2016

Real-time Sensor-aided Scene Analysis based on Line Graph

for Mobile Augmented Reality

Jinki Jung

The Journal of Korean Institute of Information Technology 2015

International Conferences

Annotation vs. Virtual Tutor: Comparative Analysis on the Effectiveness of Visual Instructions in Immersive Virtual Reality

Hyeopwoo Lee, Hyejin Kim, Diego Vilela Monteiro, Youngnoh Goh, Daseong Han, Hai-Ning Liang, Hyun

Seung Yang, and Jinki Jung

18th IEEE International Symposium on Mixed and Augmented Reality (ISMAR 2019) 2019

Ensuring Safety in Augmented Reality from Trade-off Between Immersion and Situation Awareness

 $\textbf{\textit{Jinki Jung,}} \ \textbf{\textit{Hyeopwoo Lee, Jeehye Choi, Abhilasha Nanda, Uwe Grünefeld, Tim Claudius Stratmann, Wilkong Choi, Cho$

Heuten

17th IEEE International Symposium on Mixed and Augmented Reality (ISMAR 2018) 2018

Guiding Smombies: Augmenting Peripheral Vision with Low-Cost Glasses to Shift the Attention of Smartphone Users

Uwe Grünefeld, Tim Claudius Stratmann, **Jinki Jung,** Hyeopwoo Lee, Jeehye Choi, Abhilasha Nanda, Wilko

Heuten

17th IEEE International Symposium on Mixed and Augmented Reality (ISMAR 2018) 2018

 $\ An \ Adaptive \ Augmented \ Reality \ Interface for \ Hand \ based \ on \ Probabilistic \ Approach$

Jinki Jung, Hyeopwoo Lee, and Hyun Seung Yang

14th IEEE International Symposium on Mixed and Augmented Reality (ISMAR 2015) 2015

JINKI JUNG PAGE 3

Real-time sensor-fusion based Indoor Localization for Mobile Augmented Reality	
Jinki Jung, Hyeopwoo Lee, Luis Weruaga, Jamal Zemerly and Hyun Seung Yang 20th International Conf. on Virtual Systems and Multimedia (VSMM 2014)	2014
20th international conf. on virtual systems and waternedia (vsiviv) 2017)	2014
Augmented Keyboard: a Virtual Keyboard Interface for Smart glasses	
Jinki Jung, Jinwoo Jeon, Hyeopwoo Lee, Kichan Kwon, Jamal Zemerly, Hyun S Yang	
ACM SIGGRAPH International Conference on Virtual-Reality Continuum and its Applications in	
Industry (VRCAI 2014)	2014
Smartphone as an augmented reality authoring tool via multi-touch based 3D interaction method	
Jinki Jung, Jihye Hong, Sungheon Park, Hyun S Yang	
ACM SIGGRAPH International Conference on Virtual-Reality Continuum and its Applications in	
Industry (VRCAI 2012)	2012
Efficient 3D content authoring framework based on mobile AR	
Sang-Wook Lee, Jinki Jung , Jihye Hong, Suwon Lee, Hyunwoo Cho, Hyun Seung Yang	
18th International Conf. on Virtual Systems and Multimedia (VSMM 2012)	2012
AR paint: a fusion system of a paint tool and AR	
Suwon Lee, Jinki Jung, Jihye Hong, JB Ryu, Hyun S Yang	2042
International Conference on Entertainment Computing (ICEC 2012)	2012
AR postcard: the augmented reality system with a postcard	
Hyunwoo Cho, Jinki Jung , Kyusung Cho, Yong-Ho Seo, Hyun S Yang	
ACM SIGGRAPH International Conference on Virtual-Reality Continuum and its Applications in	
Industry (VRCAI 2011)	2011
Mahila Augmented Beality using coalable recognition and tracking	
Mobile Augmented Reality using scalable recognition and tracking Jaewon Ha, Jinki Jung, ByungOk Han, Kyusung Cho, Hyun Seung Yang	
Virtual Reality Conference (VR 2011), IEEE	2011
Virtual reduity conference (VV 2011), IEEE	2011
Online scene modeling for interactive AR applications	
Jaesang Yoo, Kyusung Cho, Jinki Jung , Hyun S Yang	
International Conference on Entertainment Computing (ICEC 2010)	2010
Multiple page recognition and tracking for augmented books	
Kyusung Cho, Jaesang Yoo, Jinki Jung , Hyun S Yang	
International Conference on Entertainment Computing (ICEC 2010)	2010
Real-time robust body part tracking for augmented reality interface	
Jinki Jung, Kyusung Cho, Hyun S Yang	
ACM SIGGRAPH International Conference on Virtual-Reality Continuum and its Applications in	
Industry (VRCAI 2009)	2009
Hybrid visual tracking for augmented books	
Hyun S Yang, Kyusung Cho, Jaemin Soh, Jinki Jung , Junseok Lee	2000
International Conference on Entertainment Computing (ICEC 2009)	2009
PATENTS	
A virtual keyboard based on hand recognition and implementing method thereof	
Korea Patent, 10-1559424, Co-inventor	2015
3D interaction method for Augmented Reality using multi-touch interface	2042
Korea Patent, 10-1338958, Co-inventor	2013
Augmented reality system and method of a printed matter and video	
Korea Patent, 10-1197126, Co-inventor	2012
Efficient 3D object recognition using a tree structure	
Korea Patent, 10-1068465, Co-inventor	2011

JINKI JUNG PAGE 4

3D OBJECT RECOGNITION SYSTEM AND METHOD US Patent Pending, 12/912,211, Co-inventor

Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award

Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award

2010

2010 spring semester

2010 fall semester

RECEARCH	EXPERIENCES
RESEARCH	EXPERIENCES

RESEARCH EXPERIENCES		
Virtuality for Safety		
Lead researcher Conducted researches on technology-driven safety ensuring components based on VR/AR	March 2018 – Now	
VR-simulated Sailor Training Platform for Emergency		
Project manager, Researcher	June 2015 – February 2019	
Developed a sailor training platform for emergency based on VR system that provides natural interaction with virtual ship environment.		
KAIST-KUSTAR international joint research of indoor localization and context-aware Augmented Reality		
Project manager, Researcher	March 2013 – June 2015	
Designed real-time indoor localization using indoor scene analysis that makes use of line feature and multiple sensors of a mobile device.		
Augmented Keyboard: a virtual keyboard interface for smart glasses		
Project manager, Researcher	April 2014 – December 2014	
Proposed a novel interaction design and developed a model-based hand palm tracking method for the proposed interface.		
Performance optimization of markerless tracking module for mobile devices		
Project manager, System engineer Doubled the tracking performance (FPS) on a mobile device by adapting multi-threaded architecture.	March 2014 – December 2014	
Probabilistic modeling of line-pair appearance for drawing image retrieval		
Project manager, Researcher	September 2012 – March 2013	
Proposed a novel histogram based matching method that employs the invariant properties of the pairwise line features.		
Real-time 6DOF hand pose estimation for Augmented Reality using RGB camera		
Researcher	December 2010 – June 2011	
Developed the appearance based hand pose estimation by modeling spatial structure of skin colored region.		
Real-time robust markerless recognition and tracking for Augmented Reality book		
Researcher	March 2008 – January 2011	
Developed the robust recognition performance against cluttered background by dividing the screen into multiple areas and separating the corresponding recognition results		
Real-time body part tracking and gesture recognition for an intelligent environment		
Project manager, Researcher Proposed the RGB-image based 3D body part tracking method by using Kalman filter.	August 2008 – September 2009	
PhotoGeo: 3D reconstruction of vehicles based on image based rendering modeling (IBMR)		
System engineer	March 2007 – November 2007	
Implemented the texturing module and GUI interface of the system.		
TEACHING EXPERIENCES		
Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)		
Teaching Assistant – Computer Science 101 (Introduction to programming) Developed lab materials, midterm/final exams, and overall web-based course administration	2009 Fall - 2014 Fall	
Awards		
Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award	2009 fall semester	
Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award	2010 chring competer	

JINKI JUNG PAGE 5

Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award	2012 fall semester 2013 fall semester
LEADERSHIP SKILLS	
Representative of M.S. in CS department, KAIST	2008
Representative student of AIM Lab.	2012-2014
LANGUAGES	
English – speak fluently and read/write with high proficiency	
Korean – native language	